1902 SW 170th St. Normandy Park, WA 98166

Phone: 253-653-7120 | GitHub: JoshTDesign | LinkedIn: josh-taylor-738bb218 Email: Josh@JoshTaylorDesign.com | Portfolio: https://joshtdesign.github.io/Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Senior designer and front-end developer with eight years experience as a independent design contractor for companies large and small. A self-directed worker experienced in translating business goals into successful design strategies. Passionate about the design process with a love for life-long learning.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Worked on a major rebrand for Holland America Line's graphic identity.
- Twice awarded 'Best UX/UI' for UW Full-Stack Development Bootcamp group project.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Adobe XD, Figma, Node.js, GitHub, Bootstrap, Javascript, Handlebars, CSS, Blender 3D, HTML, Color Theory, Branding

PROJECTS

COMMUNITY BULLETIN

A web application that uses geospatial properties to view and create local events and ask/offer services within your general area or community. Full CRUD capabilities and commenting system. Uses authorized login session with hashed password authentication. NODE.JS, MYSQL, HANDLEBARS, EXPRESS.JS, SEQUELIZE, BCRYPT

PAW PAIR

A simple app that uses petfinder API to find an adoptable pet based on responses to a fun personality quiz.

JAVASCRIPT, HTML, CSS

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR DESIGNER (OWNER)

Josh Taylor Design — October 2013 to Present

- Conceptualized restaurant brands for Holland America Line. Developed logos, dining room signage, menus, products and advertising layouts.
- Collaborated with a team of designers to refresh the Holland America Line brand and implement new logos and brand standards.
- Designed sign packages and guidelines for Holland America Line. Worked with stakeholders and signage manufacturers to implement environmental signage on new ships.
- Managed the production of stage graphics for AJC's Annual Global Forum.

EXPERIENCE, CONT.

MANAGER, ONBOARD MEDIA

Holland America Line — June 2006 to October 2013

- Managed signage, print communication, and digital experience on board.
- Implemented a fleetwide brand standard across all onboard media.
- Created a dynamic port information publication. Oversaw the rollout for ports across the world.

EDUCATION

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

University of Washington — March to June 2021

BACHELOR OF ARTS, DESIGN PRODUCTION

Western Washington University — September 2000 to June 2003